

Amy Eisenmenger



Objective

Curious, creative problem solver with excellent communication skills and a Master's degree in Computer Science. Seeking exciting opportunities to solve real-world issues using innovative artificial intelligence and data science solutions. Bringing 5+ years professional experience and strong programming skills.

Skills

Natural Language Processing Machine Learning Algorithms Data Mining Clustering & Classification Predictive Analysis Python (Numpy, NLTK/SpaCy, Scikit) SQL, NoSQL/MongoDB Git/Version Control

Projects

- in NLP team competition wrangling unstructured and semi-structured texts using NLTK and SpaCy, Fall 2019
- Handwritten Multi-Digit Recognition Trained CNN on MNIST dataset using Pytorch, collected new data, used image segmentation and bounding boxes to achieve 95% test accuracy on novel 5-digit numbers, Fall 2019
- Beverage Data Analysis Applied PCA, kclustering, and sentiment analysis to data and reviews on thousand of beverages pulled from this API, Spring 2019
- Pacman AI Agents Coded Pac-Man players using classic algorithms like A* Search, Minimax, Expectimax, and Q-Learning, Spring 2018
- Core Machine Learning Algorithms -Coded Perceptron, SVM, Linear Classifiers, Logistic Regression, and Ensembles from scratch in Python, Fall 2018
- Completed TryHackMe Advent of Cyber learned basics of cyber-security through daily challenges, December 2019

Education

Data Scientist

University of Utah

Master of Science in Computer Science

Expected May 2020

Relevant coursework includes Natural Language Processing, Data Mining, Clustering, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Information Retrieval, Computer Vision, Image Processing, Robotics, and Advanced Algorithms - 3.86 GPA

Bard College, NY

Bachelor of Arts in Ecology with Honors

August 2008 - May 2013

Excellence and Equal Cost Scholarship and William Vogt '25 Memorial Prize in Ecology recipient. Invited to present capstone research project to the Board of Directors -3.78 GPA

Experience

University of Utah

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2018 - Present

Assisted professors of Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Data Structures and Algorithms to create and grade assignments and exams, hold help hours, and lead labs.

Software Engineer / Interim Department Director

Oct 2017 - Aug 2018

Lead team of mid-level and senior engineers due to leadership skills, interdepartment rapport, and technical knowledge. Worked closely with the CTO and COO to integrate technology into the e-commerce start-up, and advice cross-department teams on technology solutions.

- Optimized Cotopaxi's website load time using current best practices—saved \$80,000 in third-party contracts annually
- Applied Agile methodology to streamline quality projects in a fast-paced environment
- Trained two new mid-level engineers to write quality production code in our tech ecosystem
- Maintained websites, internal apps, databases, and AWS servers
- Volunteered 10% of time at Best Friends and Wasatch Community Gardens

Cotopaxi

Junior Software Engineer

Jan 2017 - Oct 2017

Worked with the Director of Engineering to maintain website and existing applications. Independently learned new technologies including data scraping, machine learning, and database design. Published production code daily.

- Automated unique product replacement with a Ruby/Shopify REST API/Netsuite/PostgreSQL integration — boosted product sales 500%
- Built a product recommendation system for Cotopaxi products using Python/NLTK
- Designed relational databases and wrote AngularJS and iOS/Android apps to facilitate adventure race registration and participation

Cotopaxi

Software Engineering Intern

April 2016 - Jan 2017

Mentored by department director to develop multiple websites, mobile apps, and internal tools.

- Created event management interface to create/edit participant information and send legal wavers using Javascript/MongoDB/DocuSign — boosted engineering and customer service productivity 10%
- Managed the department for two weeks while director was away
- Partnered with the International Rescue Committee to teach coding to refugees





